Teiko Middle School
（ナレーション）
帝光(ていこう)中学 バスケットボール部
The Teiko Middle School basketball club.
その輝かしい歴史の中でも—
Even amidst their brilliant record,
there was a generation of five prodigies
known as the "Generation of Miracles."
10年に１人の天才が
５人同時にいた“キセキの世代”
黄瀬(きせ)涼太(りょうた)
Kise Ryota.
緑間(みどりま)真太郎(しんたろう)
Midorima Shintaro.
青峰(あおみね)大輝(だいき)
Aomine Daiki.
Murasakibara Atsushi.
紫原 敦(むらさきばらあつし)
Akashi Seijuro.
赤司征十郎(あかしせいじゅうろう)
そして
彼らを脅かす誠凛(せいりん)高校の—
They are threatened by Seirin High's
shadow and light.
影と光
（黒子(くろこ)）だから これで—
It's all over now!
終わりだ！
In the quarterfinals of the Winter Cup,
（リコ）ウインターカップ
準々決勝—
私たちは“キセキの世代”—
we beat Murasakibara Atsushi
of the Generation of Miracles
and his team, Yosen High.
紫原 敦を擁する
陽泉(ようせん)高校に勝利した
セミファイナルで待ってます
I'll be waiting for you in the semifinals.
Of course.
（黄瀬(きせ)）モチロンっスよ
I'm Just Playing As Hard As I Can
（日向(ひゅうが)）取材!?
An interview?
Yeah, for Monthly Basketball.
（リコ）そう 月(げつ)バスの
ウチも注目されてるってことよ
It means we're in the spotlight, too.
（火神(かがみ)）何聞かれるんスかね？
What do you think they'll ask us?
試合の感想とか
今後の抱負とか—
Your thoughts on the games,
your hopes for the future.
そういうことじゃない？
That kind of thing.
Seriously? I'm super nervous.
マジかよ…
超緊張すんだけど
（火神）そういうの苦手っスね
We're not very good at that kind of thing.
Don't be so weird about it.
（木吉(きよし)）変に構えないで
自然にしてりゃいいんじゃないか
Just act natural.
そうそう
自然体が一番よ
That's right. Be natural.
You're right.
そうだな
ようし みんな
リラックスしていこうぜ
Okay, guys! Let's relax!
（小金井(こがねい)）全然
リラックスできてねえし
They completely failed to relax.
Good work, everyone.
（記者１）お疲れさまでした
Th-Thank you!
あっ ありがとうございます
月バスの取材なんて光栄です！
It's an honor to be interviewed
by Monthly Basketball!
陽泉戦の迫力に
僕らもヘトヘトですよ
The intensity of the Yosen
game still has us reeling.
Anyway, it's incredible that you made it to
それにしても
創立２年目で—
ウインターカップ出場は
すごいですね
the Winter Cup only two years
after your team formed.
On top of that, you've made it this far.
しかも ここまで快進撃を
続けるとはねえ
（日向）
あ… ありがとうございます
Th-Thank you.
Which game made the greatest
impression on you?
（記者２）一番印象に
残っている試合はどれですか？
Well, it's hard...
１つには…
...to choose just one.
（伊月(いづき)）決められないよなあ
（記者２）そうだよね
ハハハ…
Of course.
あえて言うなら…
秀徳(しゅうとく)戦ですかね
If I had to choose,
it'd probably be the Shutoku game.
ウインターカップ予選決勝だね
That was the finals of the
Winter Cup preliminaries.
（緑間(みどりま)）調子に乗るなよ
Don't get ahead of yourself.
けどなぁ 負けられっか ボケが！
We can't lose!
（高尾(たかお)）
そりゃ こっちのセリフだよ！
That's our line!
Rebound!
（リコ･中谷(なかたに)）リバウンド！
Though it ended in a tie, I believe
both teams played the game their way.
（木吉）結果は引き分けでしたが
秀徳は秀徳らしく—
オレたちはオレたちらしく
戦えたような気がします
秀徳とは またやりたいですね
I'd like to play Shutoku again.
（火神）うす
Yeah.
オレらの話
してるっぽくね？
It sounds like they're talking about us.
They're probably saying they'd
like to play us again.
どうせ“またやりたい”とでも
言っているのだろう
I completely agree.
望むところなのだよ
引き分けはなあ…
The tie was a little unsatisfying.
ちょっと不完全燃焼な感じでは
あったよな
The game was simply too short.
燃焼時間が
足りなかっただけなのだよ
（高尾）だから
そう言ってんじゃん！
That's what I'm saying.
Eventually we will win.
（緑間）いずれ勝つ
（高尾）当然！
Of course.
ま その前に
でっかい山があるけどな
Though we've got a huge
mountain to climb first.
Our opponents leave nothing to be desired.
申し分のない相手なのだよ
The Eagle Eye is an incredible ability.
（記者１）
“イーグルアイ”ってのは
またすごい能力だね
そうですね
Yes. Apparently a lot of
Uruguayans possess this ability.
ウルグアイには この能力を
備えた人が多いらしいですけど
Eagle Eye, Uruguay. Eagle Eye,
Uruguay. Eagle Eye, Uruguay.
イーグルアイ
ウルグアイ
ウールグアイ
イーグルアイ
ウールグアイ キタコレ
（記者１）う… うん
は… はあ…
That's it.
Just ignore him.
ホント 気にしないでください
If that's what Izuki says,
伊月が
そこまで言うんだったら—
もう 本当に ウルグアイに—
then maybe we should just assume a
lot of Uruguayans have the Eagle Eye.
イーグルアイが多いってことで
いいじゃないか
よくねえだろ
We can't do that.
（記者１）じゃあ 火神君は？
（火神）えっ
What about you, Kagami-kun?
（火神）あ いや…
Um, I'm just playing as hard as I can.
どれも全力でやってるだけなんで
監督からすると どうですか？
What do you think, Coach?
火神君のステージが上がったという
意味では桐皇(とうおう)戦ですね
Kagami-kun leveled up during the Touou game.
I believed in the team, but honestly,
they achieved more than I expected.
（リコ）信じてはいましたけど—
正直 私が考えていた以上の
結果でした
What do you think about Aomine?
青峰(あおみね)選手については
どう思っていますか？
次は勝つっス 絶対に
Next time I'll definitely win.
（記者１）え… 勝ちましたよね？
Didn't you win this time?
He won, but he said he'll win next time.
（さつき）
勝ったのに“次は勝つ”って
謙虚だね 火神君
Kagami-kun is pretty modest.
（青峰）ありゃ謙虚じゃなくて
バカなだけだろ
That's not modesty. It's stupidity.
そういう大(だい)ちゃんはどうなのよ
What about you, Dai-chan?
I lost. Next time I'll win.
負けた　次は勝つ
That's all.
それだけだ
（さつき）
それ 言ってること一緒だよ
You're saying the exact same thing.
How do you feel about
advancing to the semifinals?
準決勝進出の感想は？
“とても誇らしい”
と言っています
He says he's very proud.
そ… そうですか あ…
I-I see...
Your next opponent,
Kaijo High, is very strong.
次の対戦相手は
海常(かいじょう)高校が有力ですが？
He says the last time we played
against them was in a practice game.
以前戦ったときは
練習試合だったので—
本格的な試合は初めてだから
緊張している—
This will be our first real game
against them, so he's very nervous.
と言っています
R-Right...
あっ ありがとう
それじゃあ そろそろ…
Thank you. We should get going now.
What about Kuroko-kun?
（記者２）黒子君は？
（記者１）あ？
What?
彼の話は外せないでしょう
We have to interview him.
あ… ああ
うっかりしてて
Oh, right.
I forgot.
All of your games were amazing.
どの試合も すごかった
あ… ありがとうございます
Thank you.
チームを支える活躍だったよね
秀徳戦でも
You supported your team against Shutoku...
The Vanishing Drive!
（火神）バニシングドライブ！
You won't get past me!
（高尾）抜かせねぇ！
霧崎(きりさき)第一戦でも
...and Kirisaki Daiichi...
...and Touou...
（記者２）桐皇戦でも
ハァ ハァ…
Kagami-kun!
火神君！ フンッ！
...and against Yosen just now.
それに さっきの陽泉戦でも
Well, personally speaking, um...
（黒子）いや…
ボクとしては その…
I'm just playing as hard as I can.
どれも全力でやってるだけなので
I didn't get to make a pun about Yosen.
（伊月）
陽泉戦は ようせんね—
ってダジャレが言えなかった…
それだけが心残りだ
That's my only regret.
諦めるな
そのうち言う機会もあるさ
Don't give up.
You'll have an opportunity
to make one eventually.
ダアホ！ 行くぞ
Idiots! Let's go.
Kagami-kun, do you have a minute?
（黒子）火神君
（黒子）ちょっといいですか？
（火神）あ？
What?
ボク 今 ちょっと
ムカついてるんですけど
I'm really mad right now.
（火神）なんで？
試合勝ったじゃねえか！
Why?!
We won the game!
The problem is what happened after that.
問題はその後です
Are you happy
氷室(ひむろ)さんと
あれでよかったんですか？
with what happened with Himuro-san?
You think you can stop me?
（氷室）止められるつもりか？
面白い！
Interesting!
He jumped on the first release?!
（小金井）１度目の
リリースタイミングで跳んだ！
（氷室）あっ！？ バカな…
Impossible...
He's like a bird!
まるで鳥だ…！
負けたよ タイガ…
I lost, Taiga.
As per our promise, I won't call
myself your brother anymore.
約束通り もうオレは
兄とは名乗らない
Yeah, I know.
ああ… 分かったよ
I can't help that.
しょーがねえだろ！
Win or lose, we're not brothers anymore.
“勝っても負けても この試合が
終われば兄弟やめる”
そういう約束だったんだからよ
That's the promise we made.
What are you two, idiots?
（黒子）そろいもそろって
アホですか
What?!
おまっ… これ捨てろって…
I told you to throw that out!
捨てるわけないでしょ
I couldn't throw it away.
If anything, it sounded to me
like you were asking me not to.
というか むしろ
ボクには あのとき—
〝捨てないでくれ〞—
と言ってるようにしか
聞こえませんでしたが
I won't deny how you felt then.
（黒子）あのときの火神君を
否定するつもりはありません
But is it really so difficult to
continue being brothers and rivals?
けど 兄弟であることと
ライバルであること—
その両方であり続けることは
そんなに難しいことですか？
Himuro-san may have a lot on his mind, too.
氷室さんにも いろいろ
思いは あるかもしれません
けど 心の底では—
But deep in his heart,
he should understand.
分かってるはずです
I just saw him walking outside.
さっき表に行くのを見ました
ちゃんと仲直りしてください
Go make up with him.
Close game, Tatsuya.
（アレックス）
惜しかったな タツヤ
Yes.
けど今はスッキリしてるよ
But I feel refreshed now.
すまない アレックス
Sorry, Alex.
あのとき オレは…
I was...
気にするな
Don't worry about it.
Athletes get worked up
before games all the time.
試合前に選手が気が立ってるなんて
よくあることだろ
それより…
いいゲームだったよ
Anyway, it was a good game.
It was worth the trip.
わざわざ日本まで
見に来たかいがあった
Alex...
アレックス…
Hey, she's cute.
（灰崎(はいざき)）お！ いい女
Are you foreign? Half?
（灰崎）外国人？ ハーフ？
Can you speak Japanese?
ニホンゴ デキンノ？
Who are you?
誰だ？ オマエ
（灰崎）しゃべれんじゃん
番号教えてよ
So you can talk.
Give me your number.
今度どっか遊び行こうぜ！
ね！ ね！
Let's go somewhere together sometime.
Come on.
Don't be ridiculous!
（アレックス）ふざけんな！
Don't casually touch me!
気安く触んじゃねえよ！
（灰崎）あ？
（氷室）やめろ
What?
Stop.
I'll hear what you have to say.
話はオレが聞く
Huh? Were you in the game they just played?
あれ？ オマエ
さっき試合に出てたヤツ？
近くで見ると やっぱ
“負け犬”ってツラしてんな
You really do look like
a loser up close.
（灰崎）つうか—
Did you say something just now?
今なんか言った？
He dunked it!
（観客１）おおお ダンク出たあ！
That's Kise Ryota of the
Generation of Miracles!
（観客２）あれが“キセキの世代”
黄瀬涼太か！
The game hasn't started,
and Kise's already on fire.
（早川(はやかわ)）いあい前かっ
ひあい入ってっスね—
黄瀬のヤツ
If we win this game, we'll play Seirin next.
（小堀(こぼり)）ま これで勝てば
次は誠凛だからな
I'm sure that's part of it, but I
don't think that's the only reason.
（森山(もりやま)）いや それも
もちろんあると思うが—
それだけじゃない気がする
What?
昨日 今日の相手のビデオを
見てるとき…
Yesterday, while we were watching
videos of today's opponent...
そんな…
That's impossible...
That guy...
こいつは
What was that about?
（笠松(かさまつ)）昨日のアレ
結局 何だったんだよ
（黄瀬）いやあ…
Nothing...
ちょっと 昔の知り合いが
いたんでね
I just saw someone I knew.
He really tried to hit me.
（氷室）本気で殴りに…
Isn't he an athlete?
こいつ 選手じゃないのか？
何考えてるんだ
What is he thinking?
What's this?
何だ 見た目のわりにオマエ
ケンカ慣れしてんのな
You're a better fighter than you look.
I hate guys like you.
（灰崎）オマエみたいの
マジイラつくわ
Tatsuya!
タツヤ
Tatsuya...
タツヤ！ あ…
オレが帝光のバスケ部に入って
スタメンになったのは中２の頭
I joined the Teiko basketball team as a
starter at the beginning of my second year.
In other words, before then,
someone else was the fifth man.
つまりその前には
違う５人目がいたんス
The most dangerous man on the team...
そいつは
最も危険と言われた男
What are you doing?!
何してんだ？
誰だ？ テメエ！
Who the hell are you?!
あん？
What?
What?!
（青峰）何だと？
Haizaki's going to be in the next game?
次の試合 灰崎が出てくる!?
Yeah.
I thought he quit.
やめたんじゃねえのかよ あいつ
He's a major player on
Shizuoka's Fukuda Sogo.
静岡(しずおか)の福田(ふくだ)総合で
主力選手になってる
Just remembering him is pissing me off.
ったく
思い出したらムカついてきたぜ
That annoying guy is back.
嫌なヤツが戻ってきやがった
（黄瀬）いない… か
He's not here.
ま あいつが
真面目にアップしてるなんて—
Not that I expected him to actually warm up.
思ってなかったっスけど
（黄瀬）笠松先輩　オレちょっと
アップ切り上げていいっスか？
Kasamatsu-senpai, can I stop warming up?
What?
まだ始めたばっかじゃ…
We just started...
Fine. Don't let your body get cold.
分かった
冷やすなよ 体
Okay.
（黄瀬）はい
放せよ オイ！
Let go!
You just beat Atsushi.
オマエ
さっき敦に勝ったヤツじゃん
I was watching.
見てたぜ
You're not bad.
結構やんなあ
（火神）あっ… 紫原を知ってる
He knows Murasakibara? Who is this guy?
こいつ 一体…
くっ… とり… あえず…
放せよ
Let go of me, you brat!
クソガキ！
Whoops...
おっと
How scary!
おー 怖っ
That's not how a woman kicks.
女の蹴りじゃねえぞ そりゃ
Alex! You bastard!
アレックス！ テメッ！
Stop!
（氷室）やめろ！
タツヤ
Tatsuya!
Stay out of this.
手を出すな！
こんな所で
選手がケンカなんてしたら—
You're not the only one who will
suffer if we get into a fight here.
問題になるのは
オマエだけじゃないぞ
何があったんだよ 一体
What happened?
He suddenly tried to pick a fight with me.
いきなり からまれてな
He was hitting on Alex. When I
tried to stop him, this happened.
アレックスに手を出そうとしたんで
止めたらこのザマだ
He did what?
何だよ それ
そんな
気まぐれみたいなことで—
A basketball player shouldn't
punch people on a whim!
バスケ選手が人殴っていいのかよ
つうか さっきから
うるせえんだけど！
Anyway, shut the hell up!
He doesn't care about basketball at all!
（火神）こいつは
バスケを何とも思ってねえ
Hey, come on.
いきなりオレにボールを
投げつけるなんて—
You've got some guts to
throw a basketball at me,
いい度胸だな
Ryota.
涼太
黄瀬!?
Kise?!
Hello.
（黄瀬）どーもっス
You know this guy?
オマエ こいつと知り合いなのか
（黄瀬）まあ そうっスね
Well, yes.
His name is Haizaki Shogo.
名前は灰崎祥吾(しょうご)
帝光でオレが入部するまでは
スタメンだったヤツっス
He was a starter for Teiko
until I joined the team.
そして…
And
Akashicchi forced him to quit the team.
赤司っちにバスケ部を
強制退部させられた選手っスよ
He was good, but as you
can see, he's violent.
実力はあったけど
見てのとおり暴力沙汰が絶えず—
He disappeared when I joined the team.
オレとは入れ替わりで姿を消した
はずなんスけど—
At least, he should have.
どういう風の吹き回しっスか？
How did this come about?
別に理由なんてねえよ
No reason. I'm not doing this for revenge.
復讐とかでもねえ
強いて言えば—
If I had to give a reason,
I'd say I'm just killing time.
ただのヒマつぶしだ
I don't care about basketball,
（灰崎）バスケなんて
どうでもいいが—
なんかオレが辞めてから—
but people starting calling you the
Generation of Miracles after I quit.
“キセキの世代”とか
やたら騒がれるようになったからよ
I thought I'd steal the title
from one of you five again.
オマエら５人のうちの１人から—
もう一度その座を
奪っちまおうと思ってな
実際 オレは
スタメンだったわけだし—
I used to be a starter.
No one would have a problem if I beat you.
倒せば誰も文句は言わねえだろ
それに次の相手がオマエなら
なおさらだぜ 涼太
Besides, since you're my next opponent,
I have all the more reason to do it, Ryota.
なんせオマエはオレに
一度も勝てないまま—
After all, you became the fifth man
うやむやに“５人目”と
呼ばれるようになったからな
without beating me once.
He beat Kise?
（火神）黄瀬が負けてる!?
（黄瀬）火神っち
（火神）ん？
Kagamicchi.
I need to ask you something.
（黄瀬）１つ
確認しときたいんスけど—
Who's that beautiful blonde?
その金髪美女は誰スか？
This isn't the time for that!
今それどころじゃねえだろ！
（火神）オレとタツヤの師匠だよ
（黄瀬）え！ マジ!?
She's Tatsuya's and my master!
What? Seriously?
マジだよ！
Yes, seriously!
I'm really sorry,
本当に悪いんスけど—
この場はここで
収めてくれないっスか？
but could we end this here?
I more or less understand the situation,
（黄瀬）状況は
なんとなく分かるっスけど—
次の試合 どうしても
あいつと やらしてほしいんス
but I need to fight him in the next game.
I'll beat him.
オレが責任持って倒すんで
I don't care about being one of
the Generation of Miracles.
（黄瀬）“キセキの世代”なんて
名前に こだわりはない…
I told Kagamicchi that once.
昔 火神っちに
そう言ったっスけど—
それでも あんたみてえのに
ホイホイやるほど—
But it's not so worthless I can just
let you have it for free, Shogo-kun.
安く売ってねえよ 祥吾君
I'm not trying to buy it
off you. I told you, Ryota.
買わねえよ
言ったろ？ 涼太
欲しくなったから
よこせっつってるだけだ バーカ
I'm just telling you to hand it over if
you don't want it anymore, you idiot.
なんでここに来たんだ タイガ
Why did you come here, Taiga?
Oh, right.
はあ…
悪い… また今度話すよ
Sorry. I'll tell you another time.
I promise.
必ず
Kise!
黄瀬！
You'd better not lose!
負けんじゃねえぞ！ 絶対！
Of course I won't!
当然っス！
おーい 火神！ こっちこっち！
Hey, Kagami! Over here!
Welcome back. How did it go?
おかえりなさい　どうでしたか？
Kuroko,
黒子…
do you know a guy named Haizaki?
オマエ 灰崎ってヤツ 知ってるか？
なんでその名前を
Why do you know that name?
I just met him.
今 会ってきた
Where have you been, Kise?
（笠松）どこ行ってたんだ 黄瀬！
You're just barely on time!
（森山）時間ギリギリだぞ！
Sorry!
スンマセン
全員準備は いいな
あとは勝つだけだ
Everyone's ready!
Now we just have to win!
Let's go!
（笠松）行くぞ！
（海常選手たち）おう！
Yeah!
What?
（日向）そんなヤツがいたのか
He's on their team?
Kuroko, what do you think?
黒子 どう思う？
He was selfish and out of control.
自分勝手で とにかく
制御ができない人でした
But it's true he was a starter.
けど それでも—
１軍レギュラーだったのは
事実です
He's definitely strong.
強いのは間違いありません
Kaijo
Fukuda Sogo
The fourth Winter Cup quarterfinal game
（審判）これよりウインターカップ
準々決勝 第４試合—
between Kaijo High and
Fukuda Sogo will now begin!
海常高校 対 福田総合学園の
試合を始めます 礼！
Bow!
（選手たち）
よろしくお願いします！
Good game!
Preview
（火神）灰崎祥吾
ヤバすぎるだろ
Haizaki Shogo. He's insane...
（黒子）でも帝光中
１軍レギュラーだった実力は—
But it's true he was strong enough
to be a starter for Teiko.
間違いないです
（火神）
黄瀬のヤツ 大丈夫だよな？
Kise will be okay, right?
Yes. Kise-kun will settle this on the court.
It's Mine
（黒子）はい 黄瀬君なら—
バスケで決着を
つけてくれるはずです